Vinoth Mani

Boston, MA | mani.vin@northeastern.edu | 857-350-5054

https://www.linkedin.com/in/dev-vinoth-mani | http://www.botbuilders.live | Software Engineer

-OBJECTIVE-

Innovative and passionate individual with 3 years of professional experience worked in different **R&D** projects looking for an opportunity to work in a growth-oriented company where I can use my skills to the advantage of the company and also develop my own skills.

-EDUCATION-

Northeastern University, Boston

Expected May 2023

Master of Science in Software Engineering Systems

Relevant Coursework: Program Structure Algorithms, Concepts of OOPS, Enterprise Software Design, Network Structure & cloud computing, Software Engineering, Web design, Parallel, concurrent & multithread programming

Anna University, Chennai, India

Apr 2018

Bachelors of Engineering in Computer Science Engineering

TECHNICAL SKILL SETS

Programming Language: python, swift, C#, java, javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SQL **Framework & DB:** leafletjs, cocoapods, Rasa Al Chatbot, SQL, Firebase, MongoDB

Source Control: Perforce, Git

Tool Expertise: Xcode, VS Code, Unity 3D, Visual Studio, Blender 3D, Meld, beyond compare, JIRA, postman, ngrok, AWS

Certification: Rasa Certified Developer

-PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE-

Associate Software Engineer, Scientific Games Corporation, Chennai, India

GDK Middleware Version Migration (*C#, python, PS script, NuGet packages*)

Jun 2020-July 2021

- Implemented and fixed code changes in C# for migration from vs 2013 .net 3.5 to vs 2019 .net 4.6.1 framework
- Redesigned GDK game and build system to run games in VS 2019 and Unity 2019

Thinclient Web game development (typescript, javascript, PixiJS, HTML5, CSS, PS script)

Feb 2019-May 2020

- Analysed and worked in game mechanism and UI for poker card shuffling
- Fixed bugs in application and optimised UI layout for slot games

Selfhelp AI Chatbot (python, RASA framework, nodejs, Facebook API, telegram API, Amazon EC2, Docker)

Jun 2019-Jan 2020

- Compiled the project entirely from a R&D to MVP and developed API, external chatbot action
- Developed a single executable windows bash file using python for bot training, validations and running up all its services
- Established the rasa backend integration with Facebook, telegram messengers and custom website UI for frontend

Bonusing based on geo-location (Xcode, Swift, Firebase SDK, Mac OS)

Nov 2018-May 2019

- Implemented all validations for user on boarding, geo-fencing and notifications using firebase API and swift programming
- Collaborated firebase Database for storage and iOS core location library for tracking user location
- Developed a user and admin application where admin app can control and decide specialization offers sent to user application

Oblivion ARLO game application (*Xcode, swift, PHP, Firebase, cocoapods, leafletjs, inkscape, postman, xml*)

Sep 2017-Apr 2018

- Developed user login, registration, password reset, on-screen validations, backend functionalities and API
- Built casino maps for treasure hunt using leafletjs and hosted it in local IIS and Amazon EC2 instance
- Implemented user authentication using firebase API and game elements for iOS with ARkit

-ACADEMIC PROJECT-

Secure File Sharing &Access in Cloud by AES and RSA – web application (Eclipse, MY SQL, Java, Microsoft Azure) Jan 2018-Mar 2018

- Designed real time cloud facility encryption algorithm for secured file sharing in cloud
- Delivered project in NATIONAL CONFERENCE ON RECENT TRENDS IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY AND COMMUNICATION (NCRTIC'18) associated with Computer Society of India for paper presentation

BALLAMOS Game development - mobile, PC, web application (Unity 3D, Blender 3D, C#)

Aug 2016-Oct 2016

- Drove responsible for design, developing 3D objects in game and score mechanism in game
- Direct apk https://drive.google.com/file/d/1pj8eUn0xQpnMwtic_r30xp8CKL4VqlqE/view?usp=sharing

-ENTREPRENEURSHIP-

BotBuilders - AI Chatbot - Web - Mobile (www.botbuilders.live)

Jan 2019-till date

- Founded and initiated to setup CAAS-Chatbot as a Service to clients for educational & training purposes
- Drafted the chatbots and made available in cloud infrastructure for seamless customer integration
- Performed training sections for different individuals in various technologies